Guide to the Thomas B. Deen papers, 1957-1995
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 5: Publications, February 1957-October 1995
  - Testimony Before U.S. House of Representatives Subcommittees, June-August 1983 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Science and Technology, May 1983 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Sciences, June 1983 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Statement of Deputy Federal Highway Administrator Lester P. Lamm Before the House Committee on Science and Technology, Subcommittee on Investigations and Oversight and the Subcommittee on Transportation, Aviation and Materials, June 1983 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - The Texas A and M University System, June 1983 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Foreign Highway Research Programs, June 1983 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Draft of Deen Testimony to the Congressional Committees, June 1983 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Planning for the Caracas Metro, Undated (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Proposed First Phase Rapid Transit Line, Undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Federal Policy Implications of Bay Area Rapid Transit, January 1978 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Digest of a Talk: "What is Transit Doing--A Framework for Discussion", April 1978 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - The Transit Way System --For Small Cities, Undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Digest of a Talk: "What is Transit Doing--A Framework for Discussion", January 1978 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - RDSA/Alan M. Voorhees and Associates- What and who are we? What do we want to be?, November 1977 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - The Changing Role of Urban Transport Planning Professionals, November 1977 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Planning for Rapid Transit Systems: Responses to a Changing Federal Viewpoint, January 1976 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Some Practical Considerations Related to Urban Transportation Planning, December 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Critical Decisions in the Rapid Transit Planning Process, January 1975 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Energy and the Consulting Outlook, Undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Sensitivity of Demand Management Procedures for Urban Areas, September 1974 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - System Design Considerations, Undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - System Applications, Undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Equipment Specifications, February 1972-March 1972 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - National Conference on Personal Rapid Transit, November 1971 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Transportation Technology, Inc., June 1972 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Multi-Purpose Transporter, June 1972 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - An Interim Procedure for the Economic Evaluation of Transportation Networks, 1968-March 1973 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Documents 84-84K, October 1958-November 1971 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Documents 84L-84Z, February 1961-July 1971 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Documents 48-65, May 1963-June 1991 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Documents # 85. 85A-85Z- Caracas Road Pricing 1 of 3, November 1973 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Documents # 85. 85A-85Z- Caracas Road Pricing 2 of 3, November 1973 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Documents # 85. 85A-85Z- Caracas Road Pricing 3 of 3, November 1973-October 1995 (Box 48, Folder 2)
- Series 6: Miscellaneous, January 1965-October 1995
  Miscellaneous files from the Thomas Deen collection. Material includes official reports, discussion outlines, meeting schedules and agendas, memos, correspondence, attendance lists, committee lists, work plans, travel information, notes, pamphlets, programs, resumes, newsletters, maps, articles, congressional resolutions, publications, fact sheets, business cards, contact information, charts and graphs, "Who's Who" articles and calendars. Subject matter includes public works, traffic management, vehicle safety, roads and bridges, carpooling, asphalt, the 55 mile per hour speed limit, traffic engineering, highway financing, federal highway administration, and railroads.
  - National Council on Public Works Improvement, Denver, Colorado, September 1986-February 1987 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Corridor Traffic Management During Major Highway Reconstruction, Chicago, Illinois, April-October 1986 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Visit of GM Physicians- Traffic- Vehicle Safety Committee, October 1985-September 1986 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Portland Oregon Plan Review, November 1985-March 1986 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Roads and bridges, Washington, D.C., October 1984-September 1987 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Mass Transit- C Carroll Carter 1981-82, May 1981-February 1982 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - People to People Program- China Tour, February 1986 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Philippines Library 1981, July 1981 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - American Petroleum Institute 1983, January-July 1983 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - The White House Carpooling, July 1979-July 1980 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Great Lakes Asphalt, Inc. 1977-80, August 1977-October 1980 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Engineering "The Bridge" Article, August 1984 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Slides, Undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - 55 MPH Hearing Committee on Science and Technology - U.S. House of Representatives, December 1984-January 1985 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Robert E. Heightchew, Jr., September 1979-November 1984 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Toxicity Hazards of Materials in Rail Transit Vehicles 1984, February-March 1984 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Traffic Engineering and Control 1981-84, July 1981-July 1986 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Institute for the Study of Transportation 1984-86, June 1984-December 1986 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials Annual Meeting, September-October 1989 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - The Road Gang, August 1983 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, March 1980-November 1981 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Yale-Penn State Class Reunions, August 1981, Boston, Massachusetts, October 1980-September 1981 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - New York Port Authority, August 1988 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Daimler-Benz, Berlin, February 1985-October 1989 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Lunch with Stephanie Lee-Miller, October-December 1990 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Council of Governments, December 1987-January 1990 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Sao Paulo Paper, January 1987-December 1991 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Brazil Trip, June 1989-October 1990 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Asphalt Institute, February-May 1990 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - National Highway Program Hearing on H.R.4260 to Create a Federal Highway Corporation for Financing the Construction of the National System of Interstate Highways- Notebook 9, Undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Maps-Santa Barbara, San Francisco, and Berkeley, May-July 1990 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Los Angles, September 1989-August 1990 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - TRANSIMS-Transportation Analysis and Simulation System, May-June 1992 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials Policy Committee Washington, D.C., January- February 1986 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Matson Fund, January 1965-May 1979 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Institute of Transportation Engineers-Financial Review Committee, December 1979-September 1983 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Highway Innovative Technology Evaluation Center-Informative and Application Booklet, December 1993-January 1994 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - International Road Federation Program, June 1974-July 1981 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Federal Highway Administration-David Phillips Orientation Associate Administrator for Research and Development, September-November 1984 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - James H. Burnley, IV- Department of Transportation Deputy Secretary, June 1983-February 1984 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - American Association of Railroads, November 1982-January 1983 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Georgetown Facility 1985-87, February 1985-August 1994 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Jim Murphy 1993, June 1992-March 1993 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Dennis Murphy 1993, December 1992-March 1993 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Facilities Advisory Committee 1987, August-December 1987 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Problems since September 1988, March 1988-November 1989 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Highway Innovative Technology Evaluation Center Application Form, July 1993 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Highway Industry Research Advisory Council, December 1992-May 1993 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - The Bay Area Partnership, February-July 1992 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Penndot- I-95 Intermodal Mobility Project, October 1990-February 1991 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Singapore Consulting 1991, January 1991 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Thomas Deen- Travel, January 1990-July 1994 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Marcial Echenique, November 1981-November 1991 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Inter Modal Minutes, Undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Papers and Reports Written by Deen, April 1986-February 1994 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Anthony Penfold 1984, May 1984-January 1992 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - T. B. Deen- Photographs, Undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Deen- Personal Resume- Bio, October 1980-October 1995 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Who's Who in America, June 1981-October 1993 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Monthly Minder 1990, December 1989-January 1991 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Monthly Minder 1991, January 1991-January 1992 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Monthly Minder 1992, December 1991-January 1993 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Monthly Minder 1993, December 1992-January 1994 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Intelligent Vehicle Highway Society Program Assessment, February-March 1994 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Information on U.S. Department of Transportation Fiscal Year 1992 Plans, May 1991-January 1992 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Advanced Public Transportation Systems-The State of the Art, April 1992 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Capabilities and Facilities, Undated (Box 52, Folder 21)